

Scott Greff 8 – 5 E 10th Ave, Vancouver, BC V5T 1Y9

Phone: (778) 389-0344

Email: scottiegreff@gmail.com

Website: <a href="mailto:scottgreff.com">scottgreff.com</a>

## **PROFILE**

A Full Stack Developer with experience in developing web applications, back-end services, and databases. Deployed applications to multiple cloud-based production environments, designed and maintained relational database systems, and integrated third-party services to ensure reliability, security, and scalability. Integrate data analytics to prove the effectiveness of stakeholder's investment. With a personal interest in music, cooking, and travel, I bring a sense of creativity to the development process, I am driven by a relentless pursuit of excellence seeing tasks through to completion. As I seek to contribute to a forward-thinking team, my aim is to deliver quality web solutions that drive innovation and exceed expectations.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Computer Science Associate Degree, Langara, Vancouver BC (2023)
- Audio Engineering, Berkely School of Music, Boston Ma, (2004)
- Grade XII Diploma, O'Neil Secondary, Regina, SK (2001)

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2022-2024 Full-Stack Developer, Vancouver, BC

Freelance Work

- Use HTML, CSS, and TypeScript constructing dynamic and responsive user interfaces.
- Implement Node and PHP for server-side languages and backend development.
- Utilize RESTful services via APIs in client-server communication.
- Design, create, and optimize relational databases and non-relational databases.
- Query databases using SQL or ORMs.
- React & Next JS for front-end frameworks and Express.js for backend framework.
- Use GitHub for version control systems and JIRA for collaboration.
- Implement robust state management solutions using Redux.
- Comprehension of web architecture, including client-server communication, data flow, and security best practices.
- Understanding of basic design principles to ensure applications are both user-friendly and visually appealing.

2016-2019 Greff Growler, Vancouver, BC

Partnership Owner

Product Design, Marketing, Sales, Production Lead

Business owner that specialized in supplying breweries with branded merchandise.

- Designed a range of products including portable beer growler holders and home bar accessories.
- Managed the logistics and supply chain coordination for the product from the point of manufacture to delivery.
- Market and data analytics using UTMs and Google Analytics.
- · Launched targeted social media campaigns to generate interest and brand awareness.
- Conducted A/B testing for marketing effectiveness to improve ROI.

- Instituted a quality control process to guarantee the highest standard of products delivered to brewery.
- Developed partnerships with local and regional breweries to expand market presence and brand recognition.
- Partnered with local events and beer festivals to sponsor booths, increasing product visibility and direct customer engagement.

2007-2018 Vancouver Public School Board, Vancouver, BC

School and Student Support Worker Tutoring Teacher for Math and Science (2014-2019) Team Lead of District Program (2010-2014)

Taught within classrooms to reinforce and provide personalized tutoring on course material for students.

Supported students with diverse abilities in integrated classrooms, special programs and in work experience.

- Tailoring teaching methods to accommodate different learning styles.
- Breaking down complex topics into understandable segments.
- Creating engaging lesson plans to reiterate classroom material.
- Helping students develop effective study and time management skills.
- Participated in quality assurance audits and program reviews.
- Participating in professional development to stay current with educational best practices.
- Assessing student understanding and knowledge gaps through informal assessments.
- Conducting one-on-one or small group tutoring sessions.
  - Monitoring student progress and adjusting teaching strategies accordingly.
- Trained and mentored support workers.
- Advocated for student self-determination, empowerment, inclusivity and diversity.
- Aided in the development and implementation of Individual Education Plans.
- Liaised with families and community supports, maintaining excellent communication, respect and trust.

2005-2007

Spectrum Society for Community Living, Vancouver, BC Team Lead - Key Worker (2005-2008) Community Support Worker

Primary Caregiver, supported adults with diverse abilities.

- Supervised, trained, and mentored staff in the needs of the clients and ensured they were up to date on client development and changing needs.
- Participated in staff hiring, created staff schedule, and completed staff performance reviews.
- Provided leadership, in conjunction with the clients, Manager and team, in determining short and long-term goals, and in the planning and development relevant to the needs of the clients.
- Coordinated and facilitated team meetings.
- Oversaw the care and support of clients in areas of health, safety, finances, staffing, and record keeping.
- Liaised with health care teams, families and community services.

### **EDUCATION** (non-formal)

- AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification
- Data Structures & Algorithms in C++
- C++ Course on low level optimization

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Developed and integrated efficient back-end services with databases, leading to a ~600ms decrease in data fetching by upgrading legacy code to newer server-side rendering.
- Streamlined codebase by refactoring components, achieving a 30% reduction in code length for enhanced readability and maintainability, aligned with best practice industry standards
- Enhanced user security by transitioning from session-based to JWT token-based authorization, tightening app security while also reducing data transfer by 45%.
- Instituted a stable global state management system to eliminate prop-drilling, thereby improving the code base's readability, maintainability, all while achieving the separation of concerns principle.

 Successfully launched multiple responsive websites that met or exceeded user engagement metrics.

# **HARD SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Python, Java, C++, SQL, PHP

Frontend / Backend Framework: React , Next JS , Express , Django

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Plain JSON

ORMs: Mongoose , Prisma , Drizzle

AWS: EC2, IAM, S3, RDS, DynamoBD, EBS, Lambda, CloudFront, SNS,

State Management: Redux, Context, Zustand

APIs: REST API, Fetch, Axios, Public, Token-Based

CSS Frameworks: Tailwind , Bootstrap

Component Libraries: ShadCN, React-Bootstrap, Styled-Components, Material-UI, Tailwind-UI

Authentication: OAuth , Sessions , JWT /JWE , Auth.js , Clerk , , Adapters , Providers

Form Management and Validation: React Hook Form, ZOD, Toast

Accessibility: Aria: Screen Readers , UX/UI

Runtime Environments: NodeJS, AWS Lambda,

Security & Prevention: SQL Injection, CORS, Cross-Site-Scripting

SEO: Crawling , Ranking , On-Page Optimization ,Backlinks , Google Analytics , hrefs

Repositories: Git, GitHub,

 $Software\ Architecture:\ Model-View-Controller\ ,\ Model-View-ViewModel$ 

 $\label{eq:methodologies: CI/CD} \mbox{ Agile Development , Scrum , User Stories}$ 

 ${\sf Coding\ Paradigms:\ Functional\ Programming\ ,\ Object-Oriented\ Programming\ ,\ Procedural}$ 

Cloud Services: Netlify, Vercel, Firebase, AWS, Google Cloud, Azure

Animation - 2&3D: CSS , Spline , Adobe After Effects , Framer Motion , Blender

Graphics Editors: Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere Pro

Audio Recording: Audacity , Logic Pro , Cubase , Garage Band , Pro Tools

<sup>\*</sup> REFRENCES UPON REQUEST